<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="addon">
  <id>org.freedesktop.LinuxAudio.Plugins.DPF-Plugins</id>
  <extends>org.freedesktop.LinuxAudio.BaseExtension</extends>
  <name>DPF-Plugins</name>
  <summary>DPF-Plugins LADSPA/DSSI/LV2/CLAP/VST/VST3</summary>
  <description>
    <p>This collection of LADSPA, DSSI, LV2, CLAP, VST and VST3 plugins contains:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Mini-Series: 3-Band EQ, 3-Band splitter, Ping Pong Pan
      (LADSPA, LV2, CLAP, VST and VST3).</li>
      <li>Max-Gen samples: MaBitcrush, MaFreeverb, MaGigaverb,
      MaPitchshift (LADSPA, LV2, CLAP, VST and VST3).</li>
      <li>MVerb: Studio quality reverb (LADSPA, LV2, CLAP, VST and
      VST3).</li>
      <li>ndc-Plugs: Amplitude Imposer, Cycle Shifter, SouForce
      (LADSPA, LV2, CLAP, VST and VST3).</li>
      <li>Nekobi: simple single-oscillator synth based on Roland
      TB-303 (DSSI, LV2, CLAP, VST and VST3).</li>
      <li>Kars: Simple karplus-strong plucked string synth (DSSI, LV2,
      CLAP, VST and VST3).</li>
      <li>glBars: An OpenGL bars visualization plugin (LV2, CLAP, VST
      and VST3).</li>
      <li>ProM: An awesome music visualizer (LV2, CLAP, VST and
      VST3).</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://distrho.sourceforge.io/plugins</url>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <update_contact>hub_AT_figuiere.net</update_contact>
  <releases>
    <release date="2023-04-15" version="1.7">
      <url>https://github.com/DISTRHO/DPF-Plugins/releases/tag/v1.7</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix build with clang on non-macOS systems</li>
          <li>Fix CLAP plugins not saving state under Bitwig</li>
          <li>Fix Nekobi tuning parameter</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2022-10-31" version="1.6">
      <url>https://github.com/DISTRHO/DPF-Plugins/releases/tag/v1.6</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Initial CLAP support</li>
          <li>Stabilize VST3 support</li>
          <li>Set audio port configuration for all plugins</li>
          <li>Set VST3 categories in a few more plugins</li>
          <li>Update to latest DPF</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Plugin specific changes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Kars: Fix playback after a sample rate change</li>
          <li>Nekobi: Fix deadlock when receiving a MIDI message bigger than 3 bytes</li>
          <li>Nekobi: Make waveform slider behave as a button</li>
          <li>ProM: Fix invalid context (GL compat instead of GL3) in some setups</li>
          <li>ProM: Force keyboard focus on click</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2022-01-15" version="1.5">
      <url>https://github.com/DISTRHO/DPF-Plugins/releases/tag/v1.5</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Initial experimental VST3 support</li>
          <li>Add bottom-right resize handle in glBars and ProM, needed
          in plugin formats that can't do host-side resizing (ProM resize
          handle is invisible but still works, known issue)</li>
          <li>Some plugin GUIs can use Cairo instead of OpenGL, if OpenGL is not
          available at build time</li>
          <li>Standalones no longer require JACK, instead detecting at runtime
          if it is available</li>
          <li>Standalones will now use RtAudio for native audio device access in
          case JACK is not available</li>
          <li>ProM now ships with (optional) vendored libprojectM in case it is
          not available as system library</li>
          <li>ProM now sets up and uses OpenGL3 context instead of OpenGL2 forward
          compatibility mode, fixing usage on macOS and Windows</li>
          <li>Fix modal about dialogs</li>
          <li>Fix more High-DPI related issues</li>
          <li>Fix OpenGL context swap on GUI deletion, needed on hosts using OpenGL</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2021-01-15" version="1.4">
      <url>https://github.com/DISTRHO/DPF-Plugins/releases/tag/v1.4</url>
      <description>
        <p>DPF:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Auto-detect compiler target, fixing as-is build with ARM systems</li>
          <li>Allow to use EXE_WRAPPER as makefile option, to help cross-compilation</li>
          <li>Fix build with headers in custom path</li>
          <li>Fix "make install" for macOS and Windows</li>
          <li>Fix exported LV2 metadata to pass checks/validation</li>
          <li>Make mouse-wheel delta independent of window size</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Kars:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix audio buffer reuse, causing bad audio in some hosts</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Nekobi:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Set default MIDI CC for all parameters</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2019-07-14" version="1.3" />
  </releases>
</component>
